hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and in this podcast I
talk about ways for coaches mentors
trainers and thought leaders to grow and
get more clients in their business how
to make more money and that's our goal
and our focus is to help you make 10 20
and even $30,000 per month starting in a
coaching mentoring training business if
you're an author a thought leader
somebody with a message that wants to
impact people that's what we help you
with okay now I want talk about
something that might get
me
uh cancelled by some people ignored by
others um controversial topic that gets
taken out of context quite often um
something that you know if I post it in
certain communities it gets completely
misinterpreted uh but it's something
that's important for me to bring up and
it's something that came up on
our our live uh training during my 5-day
intensive this past
week and we were talking about about
some of the different marketing messages
and things like that and this one lady
said you know the difference between a a
scam and a and a and a legitimate coach
Mentor or trainer is
the results that they get their clients
now of course there's some truth to that
100%
absolutely um but then the conversation
went on to proceed to say that you
know a a legitimate Mentor is going to
get all of their client success and
that's where I had to pause it because
I've been in this industry two
decades there is no coach or mentor on
the planet that that is going to get all
of their client
success and any coach or Mentor that's
like thinks that that's
possible hasn't worked enough with
enough
people
and is believes themselves to have a
certain power over people to be able to
make them do things or that it's
possible to get good enough as a coach
or Mentor that everybody becomes an
ultimate success story now of course I I
think everybody who comes into Myspace
tells me their life has been
massively impacted positively but not
every person I meet becomes a
multi-millionaire does that mean that
I'm a shitty
coach a crappy mentor someone that
shouldn't be listened to somebody that's
a scam because 100% of all my clients
don't become
multi-millionaires some might argue
yes they
would which is crazy to
me and that's the standard that they put
on themselves and the standard that they
put on other
people when in
fact the responsibility of the results
in any coaching
relationship okay I'm going to pause
here as mentors and coaches we got to
deliver high quality information we have
to become excellent at our ability to
coach people we have to give it our very
best in all interactions right what
responsibility do I have is to give it
my very best to help somebody and not
hold back anything
okay by me even saying this it's a it's
a it's a demonstration of that because
I'm risking my reputation by saying this
to
you and I'm passionate about this
because I see this stops a lot of
coaches and mentors from even putting
themselves out there well I'm not sure
if I'm going to produce results for 100%
of everybody so I'm not going to launch
my
offer the responsibility of the
result of the client falls on the client
[Music]
themselves and that my
friends people don't like to talk about
because they automatically their brain
goes
to but that's what a scammer would say
you know a scammer would yeah or or wow
that removes all responsibility from you
from being a great coach Jeremiah no it
doesn't get over yourself first off SE
yeah I just said that second
off if I give the very best quality
information coaching leadership to help
somebody but they don't do anything with
it is that my responsibility some may
argue
yes I say no because I refuse to build
my business that way to where I care
more about my clients's results than
they do I meet my client
halfway and I've developed my business
to allow me to work 5 to 10 hours a
week without becoming codependent and in
a toxic relationship where I'm managing
and micromanaging and even controlling
the behaviors of the people that I coach
and Mentor there are some coaches and
mentors that believe that it's their job
to control and micromanage their people
to make them do what they should and
that a leader is to
basically force their people into doing
what they should that's called toxic
codependency something I refuse to do
it's something I refuse to engage in and
it's not sustainable and it doesn't
actually help anybody because now
they're relying on you as the reason for
their success because as soon as you
disappear they didn't actually develop
the habits themselves to be successful
without you and you might say yeah
that's great that's a that's a model for
me sustaining people in my EOS e system
no it's not you're just
creating your
own basically like people are not they
don't know how to succeed outside of you
pushing them to do something and I think
that I think that when you can a a great
mentor empowers people to not need them
and to be able to become disciplined on
their own and to be able to take action
and and and and I'm not I'm not going to
show up to my clients I've actually had
people quit my program because of this
because they told me that I didn't quote
unquote show up for them I answered
every message they posted I answered
every comment they left me but the fact
that I didn't call them personally on
the phone and ask them how their
breakfast was they felt
unserved and I'm not going to be wiping
people's noses or are wiping their butts
or treating them like I do my baby my my
9-month-old
like but that's what people
want and that's why most people don't
succeed is they're actually waiting for
somebody to show up and do that for
them and you're not actually helping
people when you do that and as a mentor
and Coach I have a firm
standard that I will not build a
coaching or mentorship
business that is built on me pushing
people to do what they should and making
sure that they are okay and so listen
yes my responsibility is to give the
best
information absolutely why is any of
this relevant to you because as you go
out there to Mentor people you need to
have this standard or you will find that
that you're putting an ordinate amount
of
energy
towards making sure that people are
doing doing the right
thing and essentially trying to control
other people's
outcomes for your own Safety and
Security so that you quote unquote don't
look like a scammer so that everybody
gets a quote unquote result you know I
started my coaching business that way
and I can tell you because I I
did I can tell you it didn't benefit
anybody those people were worse off that
I did that with than when they started
with me and I actually feel really bad
for that
fact that I ever did
that I thought I was helping them I
thought I was serving
them
no in fact I was just teaching them how
to not be
successful without somebody else making
sure that they are I gave them the same
information but I was putting the
responsibility for their result on
myself and that's a false responsibility
that a lot of beginner mentors and
coaches do is they put the
responsibility on themselves for the
result of the client you got to stop
doing that you're going to become more
successful as a mentor and Coach when
you give up that crown of trying to
manage maintain and control what other
people do their feelings their
emotions again deliver incredible
quality
coaching incred like like like I have
standard I the reason I say this and I
don't like even think about scamming
people is because I know the quality of
the stuff that I put out is incredible
so I don't even think about that and I
got people they try to slap me in the
face and tell me that this mess that
that what I just said is justifying
defrauding others and I'm just like
really like do you even hear the words
coming out of your mouth right now do
you even know who you're talking to like
I mean that in a nice way let's let's
let's be real here do you even know who
you're talking to that's how I feel like
saying to some of these people who say
that cuzz I'm like I you clearly
don't cuz if you did you wouldn't be
saying that and that's what honestly
goes on through my head you know this is
a new sort of raw unfiltered version of
me that you're getting on this podcast
and I hope that this is resonating with
you I hope that this gives you some some
clarity some impact what's the flip side
of this the flip side is that you learn
systems to empower people to think for
themselves you set your own boundaries
when you feel uncomfortable that they're
not getting a result you don't make it
your mission now to go force that person
into doing what they
should
toxic not
helpful it's super prevalent in the
quote unquote Kingdom Business World
Kingdom Ministry
world it's not
Kingdom it's it's gross it's disgusting
to me and it's not something that I will
ever engage
in and it's just it's super time
consuming because then once you scale
you got to hire people to do the same
thing to wipe everybody's noses and
butts and make sure that they're all
doing what they should and give up that
Crown create a system that that scales
without
you that's why like I teach about
business not about creating systems that
are reliant on you those aren't
businesses systems that rely on you to
do all the work are not
systems they're an overpaid
job and I think way too many people take
what they did in their corporate job and
they bring it into the coaching world
and they do all the same bad
behaviors and then that caps their
income it caps how many hours they have
to work and it limits the actual impact
they have on their clients we have had
multi-millionaire clients that go on and
succeed without us by doing what I'm
saying right
now and so if you're a mentor if you're
a coach if you're a trainer you got to
stop operating this way and you will see
way more success in your
life and anything that maybe what I've
said has challenged you and you feel
triggered by it you don't like it
you disagree with it I want you to
challenge why that is where's that
coming
from what have you observed seen what's
happened to you what have you
experienced what are you feeling that
makes this uncomfortable to hear or that
makes you think it's
wrong whatever that little thing is
that's limiting you right now in your
business I promise you that it's
preventing you from going to the next
level
100% And it probably has something to do
with what other people think or how
they're going to perceive you or your
reputation I don't manage my reputation
I worry about my
character I could not care less what
anybody thinks about me and I find that
that my friends is way more attractive
to the right
clients and that's a posture that will
make you a
multi-millionaire I'm not going to teach
you just how to dabble and make a few
bucks I'm going to teach you the real
stuff and this is one of those
strategies listen if this has helped you
please pass it on and share it with
somebody don't keep this to yourself
don't be stingy don't be greedy pass
this on to somebody
else cuz I think it'll really help them
as well plug into some of our events and
get on the waiting list for our client
growth accelerator program when we open
the doors to it again jump in we have
the best coaching the best
training try it out for 30 days prove us
I think you're going to really like it
it's an incredible program we'll see in
there talk
[Music]
[Applause]
soon